<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Some further reasons humbly offered by the sailors, to the consideration of the honourable House of Commons, for taking off the Q's and R's set upon their names in the Navy books.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B05914</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S4507B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC T49290</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52614956</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 52614956</idno>
            <idno type="VID">176193</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B05914)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 176193)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2764:3)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Some further reasons humbly offered by the sailors, to the consideration of the honourable House of Commons, for taking off the Q's and R's set upon their names in the Navy books.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([3] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Half-title on p. [1]: Lamentable case of the sailors of the English Navy ...</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: sheet cropped with some loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: California State Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Royal Navy --  Pay, allowances, etc. --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-12</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>Scott Lepisto</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>Scott Lepisto</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:176193:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 57 -->
            <p>The lamentable CASE OF THE SAILORS OF THE <hi>Engliſh Navy,</hi> MOST <hi>Humbly offer'd to the Conſideration of the Honourable Houſe of Commons.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="petition">
            <pb facs="tcp:176193:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 58 -->
            <head>Some further REASONS Humbly offered by the SAILORS, TO THE <hi>Conſideration of the Honourable Houſe of Commons, for taking off the</hi> Q<hi>'s and</hi> R<hi>'s ſet upon their Names in the Navy Books.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>WE know your Honours are not inſenſible of the great Advantage of the Fleet to the ſecurity of the Realm, Nature having placed your Iſland in ſuch a part of the watry Globe, that the Land-men cannot be ſecure without the aſſiſtance of the Sailors; nor can the Nation ſubſiſt under its own Laws and Fundamental Rights, without a good underſtanding betwixt both. The Sea not only affords you floating Caſtles, which are the Walls and Bullworks of your Nation, but it ſupplies you with the greateſt part of the Money raiſed for the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence of the Kingdom, for which Reaſon, the Abuſes of the Sailors ſeem yet the more hard in point of Pay; for thus they ſeem to have a Natural as well as Rightful Claim to their Wages. Had the Money raiſed upon Land, been the only Sum appropriated for the payment of the Army, and the Tonnage and Poundage upon Shiping, with all Duties laid on Merchandize, outward and inward, appropriated for the Navy, the Sailors would have had a very generous Allowance.</p>
            <p>We do not complain of the Allowance made us by this Honourable Houſe, it is in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deed generous enough; we are content with our Wages, had we any way to come at our own; and we are perſwaded that your Honours, when you gave us ſuch Allowances for Proviſion and Pay, did intend it ſhould be equally diſtributed accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the true Intent and Meaning of your Acts. We cannot find in any of your Acts the Commiſſioners of the Admiraltry or Navy empowered to ſtop our Wages, under pretence of <hi>Q</hi>'s and <hi>R</hi>'s. We yet believe our ſelves to be <hi>Engliſh</hi> Men, entituled to our Franchiſes and free Birthrights, and muſt judge our ſelves to be ſo, until ſuch time as we are Baſtardiſed by Act of Parliament.</p>
            <p>The Soldiers have Judicatures appointed them, whether they may appeal, when abuſed in point of Pay; But the Sailors, who are bold to aſſert, that they have done the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion as much Service, and earned their Money as hard as any, can appeal no where but to ſuch Perſons as have done them the higheſt Injuſtice, and are ſolely left to the Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of their Enemies.</p>
            <p>We are here unwilling to recriminate and urge the Hardſhips we have met with at Sea, by being put to ſhort Allowance in the Channel, a thing unknown to former Ages; we are willing to forget our bad Proviſions, the Peaſe, Bread, and ſtinking Beef and Pork we have eaten, when this Honourable Houſe allow'd us all Species good in their kind. But the want of our Pay, after theſe Hardſhips, is a Greivance intollerable, when after ſo tedious an abſence from our Wives and Families, we muſt have the unhappy entertainment to ſee them Starve at Home, and be curſt by the Pariſhes to which they are now burdenſome.</p>
            <p>We hope this Honourable Houſe is throughly ſenſible of our Hardſhip, in having our Wages detain'd from us, under the pretence of <hi>Q</hi>'s and <hi>R</hi>'s, and the deplorable Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition of our neceſſitous Families, occaſioned by this Greivance, is worth the Conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of this Honourable Houſe, as alſo of their Compaſſion. A Sailor is able by his Employment to keep his Family from the Pariſh, when his Wages are duly paid him; but when detained from him after this manner, not only he, but thoſe that have truſted him with their Stocks, in expectation of juſt Payment, muſt be burden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſome to their Neighbour.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:176193:3"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 59 -->
            <p>We would therefore humbly urge our deplorable Circumſtances as highly worthy the Conſideration of this Honourable Houſe: We hope our good Service may plead for us, and that the loſs of our Blood and Limbs in the Service of our Country, ſhall be no occaſion of the loſs of our Pay. The Story of <hi>la Hogue</hi> will be a ſtanding Monument of our Bravery to future Ages, and we had no ſhare in the Affair of Monſieur <hi>Pointy,</hi> or that of <hi>Tholoun,</hi> yet kept out of our Pay, when ſuch Commanders as run away with their Ships had no <hi>R</hi> put upon their Names in the Navy-Books. We envy them not the Bounty allow'd them; we are contented with our Wages when we can get it. All we deſire is the Payment of what we ventured our Lives to get; and we in all Humility hope we ſhall not incure the Diſpleaſure of this Honourable Houſe, when we complain of our loſs of Pay, and of our being whipt and pickled into the Bargain.</p>
            <p>All which is humbly ſubmitted to the Wiſdom of this Honourable Houſe.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
